Suraya Clemens

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

www.suraya.xyz surayaclemens@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/suraya-clemens github.com/surayaclemens

PROFILE

I see web development as a tool to combine my love of creating cool things with my responsibility to work towards a more equitable future, and seek engagements that prioritize accessibility & inclusivity along with innovation.

Outside my work in the tech sector, my background in linguistics provided me with practical experience in both logical and humanist thinking, and my academic accomplishments demonstrate that I execute top quality work.

Complementing these hard skills is my extensive experience in customer service, which cultivated my ability to identify and meet interpersonal needs, and form lasting positive relationships.

My colleagues know me as an excellent communicator, initiative-taker, thorough problem solver, and big fan of jokes.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, React, Flutter, Dart, Express, Node, Firebase, SQL, DOM APIs, Web APIs, User Auth, OAuth, Heroku, Git, GitHub, Figma, Jira, Agile Methodology

EXPERIENCE

Comprehensive list on LinkedIn

Full-stack Software Developer & Project Manager | Cedulify

AUG 2022 - Present, REMOTE/MONTREAL, QC

- Developed and maintained dynamic & responsive web application using Angular, TypeScript, SCSS, Node.js, Firebase
- Demonstrated strong proficiency in front-end development, ensuring beautiful and seamless client-side experiences
- Utilized Git version control system to manage code repositories
- Actively participated in code reviews, design reviews, and discussions on architecture; received and provided constructive feedback from/to peers to ensure high code quality and best practices
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs to facilitate data exchange between the frontend and backend systems
- Integrated third-party APIs such as Stripe and Facebook Conversions
- Collaborated closely with product leads, designers and other developers, to ensure seamless workflow from identifying needs to ideation to design to technical specifications and actionable tasks
- Facilitated Agile development processes, including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and reviews
- Thrived in a fast-paced startup environment, effectively multitasking and adapting rapidly changing business conditions and priorities

Research Assistant | Syrians Learning English for Employment in Canada (SLEEC), University of Victoria

SEP 2021 - APR 2022, VICTORIA, BC

- Planned and conducted academic study within SLEEC pilot program to inform the language-learning experience of refugees and newcomers to Canada
- Executed through survey composition, literature review, participant interviews, qualitative content analysis, synthesis of findings + graphic design for presentation, public speaking

Web Designer | Van Brothers Forming Ltd.

DEC 2020 - MAR 2021, REMOTE/VANCOUVER, BC

- Designed a re-branded marketing site to meet industry standards and attract bigger clients
- Exceeded stakeholder goals by refining site architecture, improving UX and modernizing UI
- Produced site on CMS and connected to company's domain

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development

JUL 2022, VANCOUVER, CA

University of Victoria | Bachelor of Arts, Linguistics

APR 2022, VICTORIA, CA

• GPA 4.0, Undergraduate Research Award, President's Scholarship

PROJECTS

- Morphology: Gamified learning for Indigenous language revitalization (Next.js, Firebase)
- Alatúlie: English to Elvish translator (React, JS, SCSS, Node.js)